[
    {
        "question": "1. (001) Light fixtures are classified by ",
        "options": [
            "a. the way they distribute light.",
            "b. the way they are installed.",
            "c. their width and length.",
            "d. their size and weight."
        ],
        "correct": "a. the way they distribute light."
    },
    {
        "question": "2. (001) Which light classification directs from 40 to 60 percent of its light upward above the area to be lighted?",
        "options": [
            "a. Indirect.",
            "b. Semidirect.",
            "c. Semi-indirect.",
            "d. General diffusing."
        ],
        "correct": "d. General diffusing."
    },
    {
        "question": "3. (001) Which classification of light fixture directs all its light so that the entire ceiling and upper side walls become the light source?",
        "options": [
            "a. Indirect.",
            "b. Semidirect.",
            "c. Semi-indirect.",
            "d. General diffusing."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Indirect."
    },
    {
        "question": "4. (001) What is the unit of measurement for lumens per square meter?",
        "options": [
            "a. Lux",
            "b. Foot-candle",
            "c. Candlepower",
            "d. Meter-candle"
        ],
        "correct": "a. Lux"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. (001) The efficiency range of a lamp is measured in lumens per",
        "options": [
            "a. volt.",
            "b. ohm.",
            "c. watt.",
            "d. amp."
        ],
        "correct": "c. watt."
    },
    {
        "question": "6. (002) Incandescent lamps have efficiencies ranging from ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1 to 6 lumens per Watt." ,
            "b. 6 to 24 lumens per Watt.",
            "c. 24 to 60 lumens per Watt.",
            "d. 60 to 240 lumens per Watt."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 6 to 24 lumens per Watt."
    },
    {
        "question": "7. (002) What is the diameter of a T8 lamp? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 8/2 inch.",
            "b. 8/4 inch.",
            "c. 8/8 inch.",
            "d. 8/16 inch."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 8/8 inch."
    },
    {
        "question": "8. (002) What frequency should you expect to find in electronic ballasts used in fluorescent lighting systems? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 120 to 208 hertz (Hz).",
            "b. 400 to 600 Hz.",
            "c. 2,400 to 4,160 Hz.",
            "d. 25,000 to 40,000 Hz."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 25,000 to 40,000 Hz."
    },
    {
        "question": "9. (002) What is used to power a light emitting diode (LED) array in a non-integrated LED fixture? ",
        "options": [
            "a. LED starter.",
            "b. LED driver.",
            "c. LED ballast.",
            "d. LED transformer."
        ],
        "correct": "b. LED driver."
    },
    {
        "question": "10. (003) What is a disadvantage of high-intensity discharge (HID) lamps?",
        "options": [
            "a. Low lumen per watt output.",
            "b. Lamp size is large.",
            "c. Lamp life is short.",
            "d. Restrike time."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Restrike time."
    },
    {
        "question": "11. (003) What are the voltages that the 150-watt high-pressure sodium (HPS) lamp comes in?",
        "options": [
            "a. 55 and 100 volts.",
            "b. 55 and 220 volts.",
            "c. 120 and 277 volts.",
            "d. 100 and 480 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 55 and 100 volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "12. (003) What color light is associated with high-pressure sodium (HPS) lamps? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Violet.",
            "b. Golden.",
            "c. Green-blue.",
            "d. Blue-white."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Golden."
    },
    {
        "question": "13. (004) Which type of fixture is installed by laying it into the grid of a suspended ceiling?",
        "options": [
            "a. Surface mount.",
            "b. Flush mount.",
            "c. Wall mount.",
            "d. Troffer."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Troffer."
    },
    {
        "question": "14. (004) When installing an octagon box for a new flush mount fixture what is important to ensure that the mounting method does not fail? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Box is sized to support the fixture.",
            "b. The fixture is less than 10 pounds.",
            "c. Fixture is secured using sheetrock screws.",
            "d. Fill capacity of the box to allow enough space for connections."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Box is sized to support the fixture."
    },
    {
        "question": "15. (005) What are the two types of phase cut dimmers? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Forward and reverse.",
            "b. Analog and digital.",
            "c. Positive and negative.",
            "d. Single pole and double pole."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Forward and reverse."
    },
    {
        "question": "16. (005) How does a phase cut dimmer operate? ",
        "options": [
            "a. A variable resistor is used to lower the voltage.", 
            "b. Two or more resistors are used to form a voltage divider.",
            "c. The root mean square (RMS) voltage is reduced by turning off a portion of the input waveform.",
            "d. Semiconductor switches are used to turn off only the negative portion of the input waveform."
        ],
        "correct": "c. The root mean square (RMS) voltage is reduced by turning off a portion of the input waveform."
    },
    {
        "question": "17. (005) What is the light output of a fixture using a 0-10V ballast with 10 volts on the low voltage control circuit? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 %.",
            "b. 50 %.",
            "c. 80 %.",
            "d. 100 %."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 100 %."
    },
    {
        "question": "18. (006) What type of light fixture is typically used to illuminate aircraft on the parking apron? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 500-watt (W) floodlight.",
            "b. 150W Cobra Head.",
            "c. Low-pressure sodium (LPS) light fixture.",
            "d. 1000W - 1500W high intensity discharge (HID) floodlight."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 1000W - 1500W high intensity discharge (HID) floodlight."
    },
    {
        "question": "19. (006) In an incandescent lamp, how much consumed energy is lost in the form of heat? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 %.",
            "b. 50 %.",
            "c. 75 %.",
            "d. 90 %."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 90 %."
    },
    {
        "question": "20. (006) What device is used in high-intensity discharge (HID) lamps to limit current as the lamp heats up? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Ballast.",
            "b. Inductor.",
            "c. Resistor.",
            "d. Capacitor."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Ballast."
    },
    {
        "question": "21. (006) What letter represents the American National Standards Institute's special designation code for high-pressure sodium (HPS) lamps? ",
        "options": [
            "a. S.",
            "b. H.",
            "c. L.",
            "d. M."
        ],
        "correct": "a. S."
    },
    {
        "question": "22. (007) When installing fixtures, ensure uniform lighting by ",
        "options": [
            "a. using only mercury vapor fixtures.",
            "b. adjusting fixtures to 5ยบ from horizontal.",
            "c. using only high-pressure sodium fixtures.", 
            "d. adjusting fixtures so that illuminated areas overlap."
        ],
        "correct": "d. adjusting fixtures so that illuminated areas overlap."
    },
    {
        "question": "23. (007) To ensure that the proper amount of light is provided after fixture installation, check the lighting with ",
        "options": [
            "a. a stake.",
            "b. a voltmeter.",
            "c. a light meter.",
            "d. an ohmmeter."
        ],
        "correct": "c. a light meter."
    },
    {
        "question": "24. (007) When troubleshooting a 120-volt photocell, which conductor should provide power to the light fixture?  ",
        "options": [
            "a. Load (red).",
            "b. Line (black).",
            "c. Neutral (white).",
            "d. None of the above."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Load (red)."
    },
    {
        "question": "25. (007) To prevent injury during re-lamping procedures, you must ",
        "options": [
            "a. wear leather gloves.",
            "b. de-energize the light fixture.",
            "c. wear approved safety goggles.",
            "d. do all of the above tasks."
        ],
        "correct": "d. do all of the above tasks."
    },
    {
        "question": "26. (008) Which airfield lights have yellow filters installed for the last 2,000 feet of runaway? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Threshold lights.",
            "b. Runway edge lights.",
            "c. Terminating bar lights.", 
            "d. Runway distance marker lights."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Runway edge lights."
    },
    {
        "question": "27. (008) Which airfield lights provide positive identification of the beginning of the operational runway surface for approaching aircraft? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Threshold lights.",
            "b. Runway edge lights.",
            "c. Terminating bar lights.", 
            "d. Runway distance marker lights."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Threshold lights."
    },
    {
        "question": "28. (008) Which airfield fixture is unidirectional?",
        "options": [
            "a. Runway centerline.",
            "b. Taxiway edge.",
            "c. Runway edge.",
            "d. Approach."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Approach."
    },
    {
        "question": "29. (008) Which of the following items are found on ALSF-2 approaches? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Runway edge lights.",
            "b. Runway end lights.",
            "c. Terminating bar.",
            "d. 500 foot bar."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 500 foot bar."
    },
    {
        "question": "30. (008) What color is used for the taxiway edge light? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Yellow.",
            "b. White.",
            "c. Blue.",
            "d. Red."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Blue."
    },
    {
        "question": "31. (009) One of the main control panels for the airfield lights is in the vault; where is the other panel located? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Control tower.",
            "b. Base operations.",
            "c. Aircraft terminal.",
            "d. Center of the approach."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Control tower."
    },
    {
        "question": "32. (010) What should you have available if your system uses 48-volt DC control? ",
        "options": [
            "a. An extra master sequence panel.",
            "b. An extra power supply module.",
            "c. Low-burden pilot relay panel.", 
            "d. A large battery."
        ],
        "correct": "b. An extra power supply module."
    },
    {
        "question": "33. (010) The standard control cable for an airfield lighting control system has how many conductors?",
        "options": [
            "a. 4.",
            "b. 5.",
            "c. 6.",
            "d. 7."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 7."
    },
    {
        "question": "34. (010) Which airfield vault device is used to swap location of control of the airfield lights?",
        "options": [
            "a. MA-1 panel.",
            "b. Transfer switch.",
            "c. Pilot relay panel.",
            "d. Circuit breaker panel."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Transfer switch."
    },
    {
        "question": "35. (010) What size cable is used for airfield light field circuits? ",
        "options": [
            "a. No. 2.",
            "b. No. 4.",
            "c. No. 6.",
            "d. No. 8."
        ],
        "correct": "d. No. 8."
    },
    {
        "question": "36. (011) How are the output leads of an airfield regulator labeled?",
        "options": [
            "a. X1 and X2.",
            "b. X1 and X3.",
            "c. H1 and H2.",
            "d. H1 and H3."
        ],
        "correct": "c. H1 and H2."
    },
    {
        "question": "37. (011) What size counterpoise is used for airfield lighting circuits? ",
        "options": [
            "a. No. 4 American wire gauge (AWG).",
            "b. No. 2 AWG.",
            "c. No. 1/0 AWG.",
            "d. No. 2/0 AWG."
        ],
        "correct": "a. No. 4 American wire gauge (AWG)."
    },
    {
        "question": "38. (011) What must be done before replacing an isolating (IL) transformer?",
        "options": [
            "a. Apply two half-lapped layers of tape to the connectors.",
            "b. Call the electrical superintendent for clearance.",
            "c. Cut the ends off of the old IL transformer.",
            "d. De-energize, tag, and ground the circuit."
        ],
        "correct": "d. De-energize, tag, and ground the circuit."
    },
    {
        "question": "39. (011) What feature is common to elevated airfield lights?",
        "options": [
            "a. They use a higher wattage lamp than other lights.",
            "b. They use a lower wattage lamp than other lights.",
            "c. They are built with frangible construction.",
            "d. They are sturdier than semiflush lights."
        ],
        "correct": "c. They are built with frangible construction."
    },
    {
        "question": "40. (012) The primary purpose of the rotating/airport beacon is to",
        "options": [
            "a. mark the highest airfield obstruction.",
            "b. inform pilots of their altitude.",
            "c. determine visibility distances.",
            "d. guide the pilot to the airfield."
        ],
        "correct": "d. guide the pilot to the airfield."
    },
    {
        "question": "41. (012) How many revolutions per minute (RPM) does the airport beacon turn?",
        "options": [
            "a. 6.",
            "b. 12.",
            "c. 15.",
            "d. 20."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 6."
    },
    {
        "question": "42. (012) What occurs when the operating lamp in the airport beacon fails?",
        "options": [
            "a. A buzzer is activated in the tower.",
            "b. A signal light in the vault is activated.",
            "c. Base operations initiates an emergency service call.",
            "d. A reserve lamp is placed in operation automatically."
        ],
        "correct": "d. A reserve lamp is placed in operation automatically."
    },
    {
        "question": "43. (012) What voltage is necessary to run the airport beacon? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 120 volts.",
            "b. 120/240 volts.",
            "c. 240/416 volts.",
            "d. 2,400 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 120/240 volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "44. (013) What device can be used to change voltage up or down for the airport beacon lamps? ",
        "options": [
            "a. MA-1 panel.",
            "b. The beacon motor's tap block.",
            "c. The tap changer in the distribution transformer.", 
            "d. The constant-current regulator that feeds the beacon circuit."
        ],
        "correct": "c. The tap changer in the distribution transformer."
    },
    {
        "question": "45. (013) What do we use to clean the airport beacon's slip rings? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Wood alcohol.",
            "b. Light sanding.",
            "c. Penetrating oil.",
            "d. A burnishing tool."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Wood alcohol."
    },
    {
        "question": "46.(014) What station marks the start of the strobe system?",
        "options": [
            "a.Station 20+00.",
            "b.Station 20+10.",
            "c.Station 30+00.",
            "d.Station 30+10."
        ],
        "correct": "c.Station 30+00."
    },
    {
        "question": "47.(014) How often does each strobe light unit flash?",
        "options": [
            "a.Once each second.",
            "b.Twice each second.",
            "c.Once every 2 seconds.",
            "d.Once every 4 seconds."
        ],
        "correct": "b.Twice each second."
    },
    {
        "question": "48.(014) The strobe system is capable of producing how many brightness steps?.",
        "options": [
            "a. 1.",
            "b. 2.",
            "c. 3.",
            "d. 4."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 3."
    },
    {
        "question": "49.(014) The wire that connects the flash head to the individual control cabinet is rated at",
        "options": [
            "a.600 V.",
            "b.3 kV.",
            "c.5 kV.",
            "d.15 kV."
        ],
        "correct": "b.3 kV."
    },
    {
        "question": "50.(014) When does the hour (elapsed-time) meter operate?",
        "options": [
            "a.Any time system is turned on.",
            "b.When system is in stand-by mode.",
            "c.When system is operated on high intensity.",
            "d.When system is operated on medium intensity."
        ],
        "correct": "c.When system is operated on high intensity."
    },
    {
        "question": "51.(014) What would indicate a failure condition on the lightning protection varistors?",
        "options": [
            "a.Blown fuse F1.",
            "b.Changes color to blue.",
            "c.Charring on the surface.",
            "d.Lamp L3 blinks intermittently."
        ],
        "correct": "c.Charring on the surface."
    },
    {
        "question": "52.(015) How long does it take the flash capacitors to bleed off their charge?",
        "options": [
            "a.1 second.",
            "b.1 minute.",
            "c.30 seconds.",
            "d.30 minutes."
        ],
        "correct": "b.1 minute."
    },
    {
        "question": "53.(015) What is indicated when two skips occur within 100 flashes of the condenser discharge system?",
        "options": [
            "a.Excessive dirt accumulation on the lens.",
            "b.Over voltage to the flasher.",
            "c.Misaligned fixture.",
            "d.A worn out lamp."
        ],
        "correct": "d.A worn out lamp."
    },
    {
        "question": "54. (016) After notifying the control tower, what should you do before working on control circuits? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Isolate the circuit.",
            "b. Notify your supervisor.", 
            "c. Test the circuit with an ohmmeter.",
            "d. Open fused cutouts on transformer."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Isolate the circuit."
    },
    {
        "question": "55. (016) What indication is considered \"good\" when you read across a closed switch with a voltmeter?",
        "options": [
            "a. One-half output voltage.",
            "b. One-half input voltage.", 
            "c. Full input voltage.",
            "d. Zero volts."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Zero volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "56. (016) To check the coil of a deenergized relay, use ",
        "options": [
            "a. a voltmeter.",
            "b. an ammeter.",
            "c. an ohmmeter.",
            "d. a circuit tracer."
        ],
        "correct": "c. an ohmmeter."
    },
    {
        "question": "57. (017) How are animals prevented from chewing on airfield lighting fixture cords? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Fixtures are designed so that no cords are exposed.",
            "b. Using a yellow colored fixture to scare them away.",
            "c. By applying pesticides to the fixture.",
            "d. By energizing portions of the fixture."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Fixtures are designed so that no cords are exposed."
    },
    {
        "question": "58. (017) What is used to maintain contact with the tower when away from the truck?",
        "options": [
            "a. Runners.",
            "b. Hand signals.",
            "c. Hand-held radios.",
            "d. Flashlight signals."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Hand-held radios."
    },
    {
        "question": "59. (017) What should you do just before screwing an elevated fixture coupling onto the base?",
        "options": [
            "a. Tighten the lock-ring until it is fully seated to the base.",
            "b. Twist the entire fixture clockwise several full rotations.",
            "c. Loosen the lock-ring until it is completely free of the fixture.",
            "d. Twist the entire fixture counterclockwise several full rotations."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Twist the entire fixture counterclockwise several full rotations."
    },
    {
        "question": "60. (018) Which approach lighting system maintenance item must be performed daily? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Replace gaskets.",
            "b. Clean and polish lenses.",
            "c. Check and record burned out lamps.",
            "d. Check and record secondary amperage readings."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Check and record burned out lamps."
    },
    {
        "question": "61. (018) When should you check all approach light fixtures for alignment? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Weekly.",
            "b. Biweekly.",
            "c. Once a year.",
            "d. Twice a year."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Twice a year."
    },
    {
        "question": "62. (019) Where is the precision approach path indicator (PAPI) system located? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Always facing north.",
            "b. Always facing south.",
            "c. On the left side of the runway.",
            "d. On the right side of the runway."
        ],
        "correct": "c. On the left side of the runway."
    },
    {
        "question": "63. (019) What occurs when a precision approach path indicator (PAPI) unit gets misaligned by more than ยฝ degree up or 1 degree down?",
        "options": [
            "a. A buzzer sounds in the tower cab.",
            "b. A tilt switch opens the entire circuit.",
            "c. A warning light is turned on at the unit.",
            "d. A warning light is turned on at the vault."
        ],
        "correct": "b. A tilt switch opens the entire circuit."
    },
    {
        "question": "64. (020) How often are dielectric oil tests made on airfield regulators?",
        "options": [
            "a. Monthly.",
            "b. Quarterly.",
            "c. Semiannually.",
            "d. Annually."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Annually."
    },
    {
        "question": "65. (020) When you tie together two airfield light circuits for emergency operation, what do you do to prevent regulator overload?",
        "options": [
            "a. Increase regulator current output.",
            "b. Remove every third airfield light from the new circuit.",
            "c. Move the control wire from step 5 relay to step 4 relay.",
            "d. Parallel the two circuits before you connect them to the regulator."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Move the control wire from step 5 relay to step 4 relay."
    },
    {
        "question": "66. (021) What meter do you use to perform insulation resistance tests on airfield light circuits?",
        "options": [
            "a. Hypot.",
            "b. Multimeter.",
            "c. Megohmmeter.",
            "d. Signal-generator."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Megohmmeter."
    },
    {
        "question": "67. (021) To perform a direct current (DC) hi-potential test on a high-intensity runway edge circuit, what voltage value do you use?",
        "options": [
            "a. 5,000.",
            "b. 10,000.",
            "c. 15,000.",
            "d. 20,000."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 5,000."
    },
    {
        "question": "68. (021) In order to perform a direct current (DC) hi-potential test on an airfield light circuit, what do you do with the leads once you remove them from the airfield regulator? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Short both leads.",
            "b. Ground both leads.",
            "c. Support one lead and ground the other.",
            "d. Support both leads and keep them clear of each other and the ground."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Support both leads and keep them clear of each other and the ground."
    },
    {
        "question": "69. (021) When using radios, which two words should you use to describe circuit conditions? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Off/on.",
            "b. Go/no-go.",
            "c. Open/closed.",
            "d. Inside/outside."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Open/closed."
    },
    {
        "question": "70. (021) Which method of troubleshooting is potentially destructive, and should not be used first? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Insulation resistance testing.",
            "b. Intentional grounding.", 
            "c. Intentional opening.",
            "d. Cable tracing."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Intentional grounding."
    }
]